<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en, zh-TW"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ricethchang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ricethchang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en, zh-TW"/><updated>2026-01-06T16:04:16+08:00</updated><id>https://ricethchang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Plant Stress Resilience Lab</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Happy 2026! May the resilience always with us!</title><link href="https://ricethchang.github.io/blog/2026/new-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy 2026! May the resilience always with us!"/><published>2026-01-05T23:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2026-01-05T23:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://ricethchang.github.io/blog/2026/new-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ricethchang.github.io/blog/2026/new-post/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Plant Stress Resilience Lab blog, and happy new year!</p> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/2026celebration-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/2026celebration-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/2026celebration-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/2026celebration.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="lazy" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> <figcaption class="caption">Happy 2026! May the resilience always with us!</figcaption> </figure> <p>As we step into 2026, we’re reminded that resilience—the very theme at the heart of our research—is more crucial than ever. Just as plants adapt and thrive under environmental stresses, we too face a year of opportunities to innovate, discover, and grow.</p> <p>In a world facing unprecedented challenges from climate volatility to food security concerns, our lab stands at the forefront of discovering nature’s hidden solutions. Here at PSRLab, we believe the answer to building stress-resilient crops lies in understanding the intricate molecular dialogue between plants, microbes, and their environment.</p> <p>This blog serves as a window into our research journey. You’ll find insights from our three core research areas: discovering biomarkers that predict beneficial plant-microbe partnerships, reprogramming fungal pathogens into plant protectors through CRISPR technology, and decoding the complex redox signaling networks that govern stress responses. Beyond the bench, we’ll update the stories behind our discoveries, practical implications for sustainable agriculture, and the collaborative spirit that drives innovation in plant science.</p> <p>Whether you’re a researcher, student, agricultural professional, or simply curious about how plants survive under stress, we invite you to join us in uncovering the molecular puzzles that will shape the future of farming.</p> <p>Here’s to a year of resilience, discovery, and sustainable solutions. Let’s grow knowledge together! 🌱✨</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Dr."/><category term="Rice"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[PSRLab PI post]]></summary></entry></feed>